<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.CardiJey.schulrechner</id>

  <name>Schulrechner</name>
  <summary>The calculator you know from school</summary>

  <url type="homepage">https://cardijey.github.io#schulrechner</url>

  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>

  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </supports>

  <description>
    <p><em>This is a very early version in development. Unlabeled buttons will be implemented in the future, and bugs may be frequent. If you experience issues or have feature requests, please file an issue (link below).</em></p>
    <p>Frustrated by the lack of free, open-source scientific calculators that feel like the ones I am used to, I decided to reverse-engineer my old calculator from school.</p>

    <p>With features like:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>input of complex equations,</li>
      <li>output as fractions as well as decimals,</li>
      <li>result storage and reuse,</li>
      <li>selection and editing of equations from input history,</li>
      <li>and support for implicit multiplication (like 5π instead of 5*π),</li>
      <li>this calculator produces math that looks like the math on your paper. That makes it much more suitable for higher-level math in school and university—especially if you've grown accustomed to this kind of interface from a young age and just forgot your calculator at home.</li>
    </ul>
    <p>Some additional features include:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>A well-established open-source math.js library as the math engine—so you're not relying on some sketchy, hand-rolled math logic (just my sketchy hand-rolled input method 😛)</li>
      <li>A familiar, intuitive design</li>
      <li>100% offline usability and fully open source</li>
      <li>Written entirely in HTML, JS, and CSS, which means it is inherently cross-platform, ...</li>
      <li>easy for other web developers to contribute and ...</li>
      <li>admittedly a bit heavy for a calculator. If you're interested in helping make a lighter version (Flutter, Kotlin, etc.), you're very welcome!</li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#7b8c86</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#40424d</color>
  </branding>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.CardiJey.schulrechner.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://cardijey.github.io/assets/img/schulrechner/featureGraphic.png</image>
      <caption>Three scientific calculators on a black background, each showing a mint-green display and rows of buttons in shades of gray with orange accents</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <developer id="io.github.cardijey">
    <name>Joris Yidong Scholl</name>
  </developer>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0"></content_rating>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.14.0" date="2026-01-24">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Feature: °′‴-button now switches to DMS format</li>
          <li>Feature: Added option to toggle between Deg, Rad and Gra angle modes</li>
          <li>Feature: Added Eng-button for engineering notation</li>
          <li>Tweak: Updated dependencies</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.13.0" date="2025-12-14">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Feature: °′‴-button now switches to DMS format</li>
          <li>Feature: Added option to toggle between Deg, Rad and Gra angle modes</li>
          <li>Tweak: Updated dependencies</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.12.0" date="2025-10-05">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Feature: Added config option to prefer decimal results</li>
          <li>Feature: Added mode menu</li>
          <li>Feature: Added CMPLX mode and i</li>
          <li>Feature: Added integration</li>
          <li>Feature: Added differentiation</li>
          <li>Feature: Added setup menu</li>
          <li>Feature: Added Norm and Fix rounding setup modes</li>
          <li>Feature: Added sexagesimal (hours, minutes, seconds) button</li>
          <li>Bugfix: Eliminated rounding errors in trigonometric functions</li>
          <li>Bugfix: Cube root of -1 now computes to -1</li>
          <li>Tweak: Updated dependencies</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.11.0" date="2025-08-09">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Feature: Added (-) button</li>
          <li>Feature: Added keyboard support for desktop version</li>
          <li>Feature: Added hyperbolic functions</li>
          <li>Tweak: "Renovate" integrated to ensure up-to-date dependencies</li>
          <li>Tweak: Updated dependencies</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.10.0" date="2025-07-10">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Feature: Added option to switch between multiple designs (although currently only the default is available, more designs are coming!)</li>
          <li>Feature: Added constants (a way to view the list of constants is planned)</li>
          <li>Bugfix: Very large results no longer cause the app to hang</li>
          <li>Bugfix: Font scaling fixed, preventing cutoff and incorrect line wrapping</li>
          <li>Bugfix: Sums in trigonometric functions are now input correctly</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.9.0" date="2025-06-21">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Schulrechner now also available on Flathub!</li>
          <li>Bugfix: Output should no longer cut off</li>
          <li>Feature: Added settings menu with info links</li>
          <li>Feature: Added option to switch decimal format for other locales</li>
          <li>Feature: Added ASin, ACos and ATan</li>
          <li>Feature: Added M+ and M-</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
