<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>io.github.CardiJey.schulrechner</id>

  <name>Schulrechner</name>
  <summary>The calculator you know from school</summary>

  <url type="homepage">https://cardijey.github.io#schulrechner</url>

  <metadata_license>MIT</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-only</project_license>

  <supports>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>touch</control>
  </supports>

  <description>
    This is a very early version in development. Unlabeled buttons will be implemented in the future, and bugs may be frequent. If you experience issues or have feature requests, please file an issue (link below).

    Frustrated by the lack of free, open-source scientific calculators that feel like the ones I am used to, I decided to reverse-engineer my old calculator from school.

    With features like:
    <ul>
      <li>input of complex equations,</li>
      <li>output as fractions as well as decimals,</li>
      <li>result storage and reuse,</li>
      <li>selection and editing of equations from input history,</li>
      <li>and support for implicit multiplication (like 5π instead of 5*π),</li>
      <li>this calculator produces math that looks like the math on your paper. That makes it much more suitable for higher-level math in school and university—especially if you've grown accustomed to this kind of interface from a young age and just forgot your calculator at home.</li>
    </ul>
    Some additional features include:
    <ul>
      <li>A well-established open-source math.js library as the math engine—so you're not relying on some sketchy, hand-rolled math logic (just my sketchy hand-rolled input method 😛)</li>
      <li>A familiar, intuitive design</li>
      <li>100% offline usability and fully open source</li>
      <li>Written entirely in HTML, JS, and CSS, which means:
        <ul>
          <li>inherently cross-platform</li>
          <li>easy for other web developers to contribute</li>
          <li>admittedly a bit heavy for a calculator. If you're interested in helping make a lighter version (Flutter, Kotlin, etc.), you're very welcome!</li>
        </ul>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </description>

  <launchable type="desktop-id">io.github.CardiJey.schulrechner.desktop</launchable>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://cardijey.github.io/assets/img/schulrechner/featureGraphic.png</image>
      <caption>The picture shows three scientific calculators against a monochrome black background. The calculator is rectangular and light gray. There is a brown rectangle in the top right-hand area of the calculator, below which around a quarter of the calculator is taken up by a mint-colored rectangular display area on which various calculator calculations are shown. On the rest of the surface, various calculator buttons are arranged in rows, usually with six buttons. The top one is blue-gray, followed by four dark gray and four light gray rows. The two buttons on the right of the first light gray row are orange. The first of the three calculators is on the left of the picture, with half of the calculator at the bottom outside the picture. This left-hand calculator is leaning slightly to the left. The second calculator is in the center of the picture, with a small part of it at the top outside the picture. The third calculator is on the right of the picture, only two-thirds visible and leaning to the right.</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <developer id="io.github.cardijey">
    <name>Joris Yidong Scholl</name>
  </developer>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.0"></content_rating>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.9.0" date="2025-06-21">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Schulrechner now also available on Flathub!</li>
          <li>Bugfix: Output should no longer cut off</li>
          <li>Feature: Added settings menu with info links</li>
          <li>Feature: Added option to switch decimal format for other locales</li>
          <li>Feature: Added ASin, ACos and ATan</li>
          <li>Feature: Added M+ and M-</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
